Sixteen!
第16拳!
Hey! He's still standing!
他还站着!
Seventeen!
第17拳!
Eighteen!
18!
Nineteen!
19!
Twenty!
20!
I lost!
我输了!
He's amazing even though he's so tiny!
虽然他个子小小的 但真的很厉害!
He's still standing!
他仍然站着!
That's impressive!
令人佩服!
I lost big money because of you, Drott!
德洛特!你害我输了一大笔钱!
What are you doing!
你是怎么搞的!
Hurry up and crack his head open!
快点把他爆头!
Keep your eyes on him!
盯紧他!
Damn it!
该死!
Something is not right.
不太对劲
My punches feel light for some reason.
不知为何 我出拳的力量变小了
Damn it!
可恶
Interesting...
很有意思...
That messenger is indeed used to being punched.
那位信使肯定习惯了挨打
Right before he's hit by the fist, he twists his neck and hips
他在被拳击中之前 就先转动了脖子和骨盆
to distribute the impact throughout his body.
让力量分散在他的全身
But it's so subtle that nobody
但动作极为细腻
realizes that he is dodging the attack.
没有任何人发现他在躲避攻击
However, Drott is also a skilled fighter.
但是 德洛特绝非等闲之辈
He won't last very long at this rate.
按照他出拳的速度 他撑不了太久的
Twenty-three!
23!
Twenty-four!
24!
Thorfinn...
托尔芬...
Even still...
尽管...
violence should be the last resort.
暴力应该是最后的手段
I wish...
我仍然希望...
I wish I knew how to choose the first course of action that's best.
自己能找到初步行动的最优解
Is this it?
是这个吗?
This is the "first course of action"?
这就是你所寻得的“初步行动”吗?
Not punching back and just enduring it all?
不还手 只挨打?
Is that how
这就是...
you are going to live from now on?
你今后的生存之道吗?
What are you going to do?
你打算怎么做?
All right!
好耶!
What's that? Are they fighting?
怎么搞的?他们在打架吗?
Hey...
喂
Come on, Drott!
加油 德洛特!
Thorfinn!
托尔芬!
Stop it!
住手!
What's going on?
这是怎么回事?
He has nothing to do with this farm!
他跟这座农场一点关系都没有!
Oh no!
不妙
All right! I felt that one!
太好了 这拳我有感觉了!
Thirty-two!
32!
That made a crazy sound!
那声音也太夸张了吧!
Did he die?
他死了吗?
Thorfinn!
托尔芬
What's going on?
这是怎么回事?
I thought you guys left the farm already.
我以为你们早就离开农场了
How did it turn into this?
怎么会搞成这样?
If he endures 100 strikes from them,
如果他能忍受一百拳
they will let him speak directly with the king.
他们就会让他跟国王见面
That's what they promised.
这是他们的承诺
No way...
不可能...
He did it for the farm?
他这么做是为了农场?
That's enough. Stop this.
够了 你住手吧
The farm is surrendering. They've decided already.
农场要投降了 他们已经做出决定了
You idiot.
你这个笨蛋
You're too nice for your own good.
令人难以置信的烂好人
If a conversation could've solved this,
如果和谈就能解决问题
we would've done that already.
我们早就这么做了
Are you sure about that?
你确定吗?
Did you really,
你真的...
earnestly,
恳切地
put in the effort to solve this
想尽办法 用和谈
over a conversation?
来解决问题吗?
Just because they took up their swords,
因为他们举剑相向
you retaliated with your sword
你们就挥刀反击
without even thinking about it.
毫不考虑
That was 32 punches.
他忍了32拳
- Let's divide the money. - He got up!
-我们来结算吧 -他站起来了
Hey, wait a second.
喂 等等
You must be kidding!
真的假的?
No way!
不可能
He stood up!
他站起来了
What are you relaxing for, you middle-parted jerk!
你这个头发中分的混蛋 你还在等什么?
Your punches are nothing more than a bug bite to me.
你的拳对我来说只不过像是蚊子叮
You have 68 more punches.
你还剩68拳
Hurry up and get it over with.
快来了结这件事吧
I don't have all day.
我没有那个闲情逸致
I have people waiting for me!
还有人在等着我呢
Stop it! This battle is--
住手 这场战争...
Einar, he'll die if he continues.
埃纳尔 如果他继续下去 他会死的
A Hundred.
一百
Thorfinn, son of Thors.
托尔芬 托尔兹之子
I'm sorry I doubted you.
很抱歉我之前瞧不起你
You are...
你...
You are a real warrior.
你是一位真正的战士
Captain,
队长
this man once served the king
这个人服侍过国王
as a royal guard, just like us.
曾担任过皇家警卫 跟我们一样
Please grant Thorfinn a meeting with the king.
请允许托尔芬晋见国王
You're small, but it seems you are well trained, Thorfinn.
托尔芬 你个子很小 但看来你训练有素
But why didn't you punch back?
但你为何不还手?
If you defeated Drott,
如果你打败了德洛特
that would have proved your skill as a former royal guard.
就足以证明你够格担任皇家警卫
What kind of question is that?
这是什么问题?
There's no point in a peace negotiation if you go around punching people.
如果出手打人 和平谈判就完全没有意义了
I met you guys for the first time today.
今天是我第一次见到各位
We don't know anything about each other.
我们素昧平生
We hold no grudges.
彼此无冤无仇
So why do we have to fight each other?
我们为什么要拼个你死我活?
It's ridiculous.
太可笑了
Canute and Ketil are the ones who want to fight.
该拼个你死我活的人 是库奴特和凯特尔
The two leaders should just play a game of hnefatafl
这两位领导人应该下一盘棋
and settle their issues.
解决这场纠纷
There is absolutely no reason
把这些人聚集在一起
for all these people to gather and shed blood.
打打杀杀 一点道理都没有
We met for the first time today.
今天是我们第一次见面
You guys are not my enemies.
你们不是我的敌人
No one is my enemy.
我没有敌人
You sure have guts
你竟敢在
to boldly deny war in front of
众多身经百战的战士面前
this many professional warriors.
大言不惭地诋毁战事 算你有种
But to think...
但你打算要...
Ketil and His Majesty playing hnefatafl, huh?
凯特尔和陛下玩西洋棋?
What's so funny?
有什么好笑的?
Pardon me.
不好意思
Try proposing that idea to the king himself.
你该亲自向国王提出这个建议
His Majesty
陛下
is not fighting wars because he wants to.
发起这场战争 并非因为他好战
If you are allowed to speak with him,
若你得以晋见国王
you will come to see his intentions.
你就能明白他的意图
Make way.
让路
I will take this messenger to the king.
我会带这位信使去见国王
Come on, Einar.
来吧 埃纳尔
We're going to meet the very person who starts wars.
我们去见见这位 发起战争的始作俑者吧
I'm sure you have something to say.
我相信你一定有话想说
Yeah!
没错
I have a whole lot to say.
我想说的可多了
All of them
有很多人
were killed in this battle?
死于这场战争吗?
Don't look, Einar.
埃纳尔 别看
Pater...
帕特...
Don't look.
别看
If you find Pater among them,
如果你看到了帕特的尸首也在其中
you'll become too emotional.
你会变得太情绪化
All right, let him through.
好的 让他过来
I'll respect your decision.
我尊重你们的决定
Thank you very much.
感激不尽
You may come forward!
你们可以上前来了
So you were alive?
你还活着?
It's been a while,
好久不见了
Thorfinn.
托尔芬
After I
我...
turned you into a slave...
让你成为了奴隶
Or rather,
或者...
after what I did to Askeladd,
我对阿谢拉特做出那种事
you must really hate me.
你一定很恨我吧
I took up a weapon against the royal family of Denmark
我对丹麦皇家刀剑相向
and yet my life was spared.
但你却饶我不死
I am grateful for your consideration.
您大人有大量 我十分感激
I am sorry
很抱歉
about the cut on your face.
我划伤了你的脸
The man who left a scar on the king's face...
在国王的脸上留下刀疤的人...
Thorfinn Karlsefni.
人称男子汉的托尔芬
He was said to have fought on par with Thorkell.
据说他和托鲁克尔战成平手
Who knew he was so small and young.
没想到他这么年轻、这么瘦小
You cut the king?
你割伤了国王?
I can't recognize you with your face looking like that,
你的脸变成这副模样 我完全认不出来
but it seems you really are the Thorfinn I know.
但你似乎真的是我认识的那个托尔芬
I must say,
我得说
you really learned how to give a model answer.
你现在很懂得圆滑的礼仪
Four years, huh?
四年了吗?
It has already been four years since then.
那已经是四年前的事了
That is enough time
这段时间
to change a person.
足以改变一个人
Canute, please leave this farm alone.
库奴特 请放过这座农场
I can't.
办不到
This all started because of Ketil.
这一切全都是凯特尔造成的
Ketil's son Olmar held a grudge because he couldn't become a thegn
凯特尔的儿子欧玛 因为不能成为臣子而耿耿于怀
and murdered ten of my men.
杀了我十名手下
I heard about that.
我听说了
But you've done enough.
但你做得也够了
More than 100 people from the farm's side died.
这座农场超过一百人战死沙场
With this many workers dead,
死了这么多工人
this area may not be able to get back on its feet.
这里恐怕无法重拾过去的荣景
I summoned them to surrender beforehand.
我先前就要求他们投降
It is Ketil's fault for misjudging the difference in our strength.
误判敌情 这全都是凯特尔的错
And that is why
所以这场战争
this battle will not end until the Ketil family is dealt with.
无法终止 直到我解决凯特尔一家人
More like,
更像是
until you make this farm your own.
直到你把这座农场据为己有吧
Your pretense isn't fooling anyone.
你的假情假意骗不了任何人
You call yourself a king, but you're nothing but a robber.
你自称国王 但你只不过是一名劫匪
What makes you different from
你跟那些维京帮派的首领
any other Viking gang lord out there?
有什么不一样?
If you want a field that bad,
如果你真的那么想要那片土地
try making it yourself.
你该试着自己开垦出来
Plow the soil, watch over it,
犁田、照料
and cultivate it yourself!
亲自播种
Then
这样
you will really understand how horrible it is
你才会真正明白抢走别人的土地
to take it away.
有多可恶
Canute,
库奴特
remember you told me back in Gainsborough,
记得你在盖恩斯伯勒 对我说过的话吗?
that you will make a paradise on earth,
你要为那些受苦受难的人
a utopia for those who are suffering?
在地球上创造一个天堂、一个乌托邦
Is that still your wish?
这仍然是你的愿望吗?
A gang lord, huh?
帮派首领 是吗?
Indeed,
没错
I am the Viking gang lord of all Viking gang lords.
我就是所有维京帮派首领的首领
I am the emperor.
我是帝王
The strongest Viking of the North Sea.
是北海最强的维京人
The ruler of the largest territory in the Nordic region.
是北欧最大版图的支配者
The commander
是数千艘船只
of thousands of ships and tens of thousands of soldiers.
上万兵马的统帅
My power exceeds human understanding
我拥有凡人无法理解的力量
and makes the impossible possible.
能够化腐朽为神奇
Look!
你看
I will calm those waves with my power.
见识我镇压汹涌波涛的能力
In the name of Canute, the emperor,
以库奴特帝王之名
I order the waves to calm down!
我命令波涛恢复平静
Did you see my power?
你们见识到我的力量了吗?
I cannot even stop the rippling waves.
我连荡漾的涟漪都阻止不了
Do you know who is making
你们知道波浪
those waves?
是谁造成的吗?
It's God.
是神
Creating a paradise on earth
在地球上创造天堂
means going against the rules he has set.
就表示要违法他设定的法则
It's a rebellion against God.
这是反叛神的行为
As long as we abide by his rules,
只要我们遵守他订下的规则
humans cannot find happiness.
人类就无法获得幸福
Rebellion?
反叛?
Look at us, Thorfinn.
看看我们 托尔芬
Look at us, Vikings.
看看我们维京人
We are the bearers of chaos and destruction,
我们带来了混乱和破败
the plunderers of terror.
我们是恐怖的掠夺者
Do you think we have the right to live in paradise?
你认为我们还有资格住在天堂吗?
But that is exactly what humans are.
但这就是人类的天性
We encompass
人类的本质
the very essence of sinning, wandering humans.
就是罪恶、就是错乱
I must save these people who were abandoned by God,
我必须拯救这群被神遗弃的人
or else building a paradise will be impossible.
不然创造天堂 根本是痴人说梦
Saving the Vikings?
拯救维京人?
That's right.
没错
Subjugating them, controlling them,
征服他们 控制他们
unifying their power,
统一他们的力量
and leading them to paradise is something
只有我能够带领他们
only I can do.
前往天堂
I need power.
我需要力量
I will unify the power of humans
我会整合人类的力量
and fight against God.
与神作战
You're an incredible man, Canute.
库奴特 你是一位了不起的人
I've never even thought about
我从来没想过
saving the Vikings.
拯救维京人
I am going to smack you.
我要揍扁你
I don't give a damn about whatever
我才不管你脑袋里
big plans you have in mind.
装着什么伟大计划
But if you are going to kill people today just for that,
但为了你的计划 你要在今天对这些人大开杀戒
who is going to save them?
那谁来拯救他们?
You save Vikings because they give you power,
你拯救维京人是因为他们给了你权力
but you kill and rob from people
但你却肆意杀害、抢夺
who are useless to you?
那些对你没有利用价值的人?
Building paradise? Don't make me laugh!
创造天堂?别让我笑掉大牙
I had
埃塞尔雷德国王
my village burned down by King Ethelred
烧毁了我的村子
and my family killed by King Sweyn.
斯韦恩王杀光了我全家人
I don't care what kind of ideals they had.
我不管他们有什么理想
I've had enough!
我受够了
I will not be a victim to you people anymore.
我再也不要成为你们这种人的牺牲品
Hate me if you want.
你尽管憎恨我吧
I don't need your forgiveness.
我不需要你的体谅
What did you say?
你说什么?
Stop it, Einar.
住口 埃纳尔
Canute, let me ask you again.
库奴特 我再问你一次
Do you have any intention of leaving this farm?
你打算放过这座农场吗?
No. I need Ketil's wealth for my project.
不可能 我需要凯特尔的财富 才能执行我的计划
So what will you do, Thorfinn?
你打算怎么做 托尔芬?
Will you kill me right here, right now?
你会在此时此地杀了我吗?
If you don't kill me,
唯有杀了我
there is no way to stop me.
才能阻止我
"Two paths."
两条路
Subtitle translation by: Kiko Morita
字幕翻译:朱未耒